CHRISTOPHER ELLIS

Salt Lake City, UT 84109 Phone: 385.421.0733

Email: christopher.ryan.ellis@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-ellis-b018a67/ GitHub: https://github.com/Arnette110

Portfolio: https://arnette110.github.io/Updated-Portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Customer Service and experience in database management and business operations. Reliable and successful in setting priorities and meeting deadlines. Detail oriented, with devotion to accuracy and efficiency.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Applications: Microsoft & Mac platforms, VSCode, GitBash

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Bulma, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Node.js

PROJECTS

Scrabble Party App

<u>GitHub - https://github.com/Arnette110/Scrabble-Party-App</u> <u>Deployed - https://arnette110.github.io/Scrabble-Party-App/</u>

- A dictionary app with a SoundCloud widget embedded designed to accompany a rousing game of Scrabble.
- Responsible for the overall layout and design.
- Implemented jQuery/AJAX call for dictionary API in dictionary.js.
- Created with HTML, CSS/Bulma, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX.

Wild Weather App

<u>GitHub - https://github.com/Arnette110/Wild-Weather-App</u> Deployed - https://arnette110.github.io/Wild-Weather-App/

- This is a weather dashboard application that includes search functionality for finding current weather conditions and a future forecast for multiple cities around the world.
- Responsible for all aspects of project.
- Created with HTML, CSS/Bulma, jQuery and AJAX.

Wonderful Workday Planner

<u>GitHub - https://github.com/Arnette110/Wonderful-Workday-Planner</u> Deployed - https://arnette110.github.io/Wonderful-Workday-Planner/

- This application is a day planner that allows the user to save events, via local storage, for each hour of the day.
- Responsible for all aspects of project.
- Created with HTML, CSS/Bootstrap, jQuery.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tire/Alignment Technician

Foothill Tire Pros | March 2018 - Current

Completes all aspects of changing tires on customer vehicles

Performs alignment adjustments

Coordinates with other team members to ensure efficiency and accuracy of work

Tele-Underwriter

Equitable Life and Casualty | April 2015 - December 2016

Performed medical underwriting interviews with insurance applicants; inbound and outbound calls

Provided assistance and guidance to Agents and Co-workers with underwriting inquiries

Assisted QA department with usability testing of new software

Received Employee of the Week Award for outstanding performance and service multiple times

Client Manager

Chartlogic, Inc | June 2013 - February 2015

Educated clients on the effective use of Chartlogic software

Proactively reached out to clients to resolve software challenges and create prompt resolution plans

Provided troubleshooting support for incoming issue calls; actively listened to client concerns

Performed usability testing for software updates

Upscale Brand Hotel Reservations Sales Agent (English/German Speaking)

Intercontinental Hotels Group | September 2009 – June 2013

Sold five-star hotel room accommodations and paid loyalty programs to travelers

Consistently ranked among the top performers in the department (10% above peers weekly)

Received multiple Intercontinental Elite awards for recognition of top performance

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: *University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT (in progress)*

A 24-week intensive, Full Stack Web Development, program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.js.

Bachelor of Arts Degree: University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

A degree in the field of International Studies with an emphasis on the study of International Business and German Linguistics.

<u>Undergraduate Coursework: Christian Albrechts Universität zu Kiel, Kiel, Schleswig-Holstein, Germany</u> Undergraduate summer study in German linguistics and culture.